Guide to Camp Young Judaea Collection, 1949-2012 MS 734
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Camp Young Judaea Collection
1949-2012
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Camp Young Judaea (Texas)
MS 734
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
Artifacts, marketing materials, newsletters, and organizational materials document activities, events, news, and operations of Camp Young Judaea in Texas and the surrounding region from 1949-2012.
Biographical / Historical
Young Judaea is the oldest Zionist youth movement in the United States. They have brought together thousands of Jewish youth from across the country and around the world – of every religious, cultural, and political persuasion, through a shared commitment to Jewish values, Jewish pride, and love of Israel. Each year more than 2,000 campers - grades 2nd to 12th - and staff attend Young Judaea's network of day and overnight summer camps located around the country.
Camp Young Judaea - Texas is a traditional, residential, Jewish camp founded in 1952. They are a co-ed camp that accepts campers between 2nd and 9th grade, (ages 7 to 14), and typically have 300 campers per session. There are two sessions every summer, each three weeks long. The campground is located near Austin, Texas, in Wimberley. Staff expose campers to a number of activities designed to educate, inspire, and enrich the lives of their campers.
Excerpted from: Camp Young Judaea Texas https://www.youngjudaea.org/summer-camps/camp-young-judaea-texas/
Scope and Contents
The Camp Young Judaea Collection consists of 1 box which contains artifacts, marketing materials, newsletters, and organizational materials that document the activities and operations of Camp Young Judaea in Texas and the surrounding region from 1949-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Outlook newsletters donated by Joseph A. Kornfeld for the Houston Jewish History Archive via Josh Furman, Feb. 19, 2018, with the exception of the 1998, v. XVII, Issue 3, which was donated by Karen Rubinsky. All remaining items donated by Karen Rubinsky for the Houston Jewish History Archive via Josh Furman April 12, 2018., Feb. 19, 2018
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series: Series I: Artifacts Series II: Marketing Materials Series III: Newsletters Series IV: Organizational Materials
Index Terms
Subjects
Jewish camps; Religious camps; Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
newsletters
Places
Texas
- Series I: Memorabilia, 2012
  - Camp Young Judaea "60th Anniversary" reusable water bottles (2), 2012 (Box 1)
  - Camp Young Judaea "60th Anniversary" t-shirts (2), 2012 (Box 1)
  - Camp Young Judaea buttons (2), n.d. (Box 1)
- Series II: Marketing Materials, 1992-2012
  - Pamphlets, 1992-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "60th Anniversary" Notepads, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising Material, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendar, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series III: Organizational Materials, 1997-2001
  - Address Lists, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Manuals, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Peulot Kit, 1998-02 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CYJ Alma Mater, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 50th Anniversary CYJ - Texas Memory Book, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Newsletters, 1949-1998
  - The CYJ ROAR, 1997-07 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Camp Young Judaea Times, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sta'm, 1995-06-30 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - CYJ - TOL (Texas, Oklahoma, Louisiana) "OUTLOOK", 1949-1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)